我听说 大号避孕套基本上
I heard Magnum condoms are basically
和普通避孕套尺寸一样
the same size as regular condoms.
嗯嗯
Mmm-mmm.
这让你思考
Which makes you think, like,
我们还相信了什么 仅仅因为营销
what else do we believe just because of marketing?
就像 如果你从小
Like, if you grew up being told
就被告知摩门经是假的
the Book of Mormon is fake,
你可能会相信它是假的 因为
you'd probably believe it was fake 'cause
别人就是这么告诉你的
that's what you were told.
不 大号避孕套很大
No, Magnums are huge.
我姐姐说她前夫的阴茎大得吓人
My sister said her ex-husband had a scary big peen,
大得吓人 他们必须戴大号避孕套
like, frighteningly big, and they had to wear Magnums.
听起来像是编造的
Sounds made up.
象鼻
Elephant trunk.
对 她就是这么叫的
Yup. That's what she would call it.
我当时在看一个视频
I was watching this video,
我不确定是在哪里看到的
I'm not sure where I saw it.
是两个人在做爱
It was these two people having intercourse,
性交
um, sexual intercourse,
做爱 然后  有一个摄影师在拍他们
sex, and, uh, and a cameraman filming them.
像业余色情片 那种类型的
Like an amateur porno... nography type thing?
视频里的女孩大声呻吟
Um, and the girl in the video was moaning loudly,
我想 在那种视频里很典型
as in typical, I assume, in that kind of video.
只是尖叫
Just screaming.
然后 突然间
And then, all of a sudden,
在镜头外 在走廊里
off camera, in the hallway,
你听到一个女士隔着墙大喊
you hear this lady yell, through the wall,
“我们能听到你”
"We can hear you!"
然后这对夫妇停止了做爱
And the couple stop sex-ing.
他们脸上尴尬和恐惧的表情
And the look of embarrassment and horror on their faces
太痛苦了
was so painful.
那个色情片女主角 就像
And the porno-girl who's, like,
从后面被进入 她说了一些挑衅的话 比如
taking it from behind-ish, says something defiant, like,
“好啊” 小声地说
"Good!" under her breath,
但你可以看到她的灵魂
but you can literally see her soul
当时就被吸走了
being sucked out of her body, right then and there.
她所有的尊严都消失了
All of her dignity gone,
好像第一次意识到 比如
as if realizing for the first time, like,
“哇 这就是我的生活
"Wow, this is my life,
“我在镜头前和一个陌生人做爱 为了钱”
"I'm f-ing a stranger on camera for money."
我只是想
And I just thought,
“哇 这真的很令人心酸”
"Like, wow, that is really poignant."
因为 就像 在那一刻
Because, like, in that moment,
我就像 “是的”
I was like, "Yeah."
上帝是真的
God's real.
我们有灵魂
We have souls.
这是神圣的确认
It's divine confirmation.
你经常看
Do you watch a lot of...
不 我不看 不
No! I do not! No.
- 我不看色情片 - 好吧
- I do not watch porno-ography. - Okay, okay.
不
No.
- 没关系 - 不 我说了不
- It's okay. - No! I said no!
- 我不是 - 嗯哼 我知道
- I'm not! - Mmm-hmm. I know.
- 不是色情片观众 - 好吧
- Not a pornography watcher. - Okay. Okay.
哦 我希望一切顺利
Oh, I hope this goes well.
我知道这不是一场比赛
I know it's not a competition,
但我还没在我的传教中给
but I haven't baptized a single investigator
一个调查者施洗
on my mission yet.
没关系 我只转变了
It's okay, I've only converted,
- 大概八九个人 - 八九个
- like, eight or nine people. - Eight or nine?
天啊
Balls.
总之 你觉得我刚才说的怎么样
Anyway, what do you think about what I was saying?
色情片的事
The porno thing?
就像
Like...
上帝是如何向你证明教会是真的
How has God shown you that the church is true?
我不知道 我想我还没有
I don't know. I guess I haven't really...
我还没有想过
I haven't really thought about it.
但你知道它是真的
But you know it's true.
若你们在信心的试炼
If ye receive no witness
之后才得到见证
until after the trial of your faith...
若你们在信心的试炼
If ye receive no witness...
我们还有谁
Who do we have...
在这对夫妇之后
after this couple again?
我想我们还有在好市多遇到的那个秃头男人
I think we have the bald guy we met at Costco.
好的 哦 对
Okay. Oh, yeah.
好的 每上一层楼梯
Okay, for every flight of stairs...
- 是吗 - 我们的丈夫
- Yeah? - ...our husband
就会变得更帅五倍
gets five times hotter.
嗨 下午好 女士 我叫巴恩斯姐妹
Hi, good afternoon, ma'am. My name is Sister Barnes,
这是我的同伴 帕克斯顿姐妹
and this is my companion, Sister Paxton.
你有兴趣了解
Are you interested in learning
我们的救世主耶稣基督吗
about our savior, Jesus Christ?
好的
Okay.
- 嗨 - 下午好
- Hi! - Good afternoon.
- 嗨 你有兴趣 - 我叫
- Hi, are you interest... - My name is, uh,
巴恩斯姐妹 还有
Sister Barnes, and...
你有没有觉得唱歌的时候
You ever feel like when you sing,
音调太高或太低
it's, like, too high or too low?
我不太喜欢唱歌
I don't really like to sing.
我觉得你的声音很美
I think you have a beautiful voice.
我知道我的声音不好听 但是
I know I don't have a beautiful voice, but...
不 你有
No, you do. You do.
我很喜欢
I enjoy it.
哦 天啊 我已经爱上这些女孩了
Oh, my gosh. I already love these girls.
嘿
Hey...
抱歉
Sorry!
抱歉 我们能拍张照吗
Sorry! Can we get a pic?
哦 当然
Oh, of course!
这里
Uh, here.
- 这是真的吗 - 什么真的
- Is it true? - Is what true?
- 你们穿魔法内衣吗 - 什么
- Do you wear magic underwear? - What?
哦 天啊 走吧 我们走
Oh, my gosh! Come on, let's go.
就是这样
This is it.
人们觉得我们很奇怪
People think we're weird.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
我不知道 那部《南方公园》音乐剧
I don't know. That  South Park  musical
有点取笑我们
kind of makes fun of us.
我听了其中的一些歌曲
I listened to some of the songs,
它们其实挺有趣的
and they're actually pretty funny.
总之 谁在乎别人怎么想
Anyway, who... who cares what people think?
你很棒
You're awesome.
谢谢
Thanks.
嗨 我是帕克斯顿姐妹 嗨
Hi, I'm Sister Paxton. Hi.
你好 我是帕克斯顿姐妹 这是我的同伴
Hello, I'm Sister Paxton. This is my companion,
巴恩斯姐妹
Sister Barnes.
上帝拣选先知
God chooses prophets,
例如亚当
such as Adam,
挪亚 亚伯拉罕和摩西
Noah, Abraham and Moses.
先知教导关于上帝的事 并接受启示
The prophets teach about God and receive revelation.
好的
All right.
让我们给你施洗
Let's get you a baptism.
好的
Okay.
啊
Ah!
下午好
Good afternoon.
- 嗨 - 下午好
- Hi. - Good afternoon.
我是帕克斯顿姐妹 这是我的同伴 巴恩斯姐妹
I'm Sister Paxton, and this is my companion, Sister Barnes.
你是里德先生吗
Um, are you Mr. Reed?
我是 你们好
I am. Hello to you.
- 你好 等等 - 嗨
- Hello. Wait. - Hi.
你是帕克斯顿 你是巴恩斯
You are Paxton, you are Barnes.
- 巴恩斯 -  不 我是
- Barnes? - Um, no. I'm...
- 帕克斯顿 巴恩斯 - 巴恩斯 对
- Paxton, Barnes. - Barnes, yes.
- 帕克斯顿 巴恩斯 - 对
- Paxton, Barnes. - Yeah.
里德先生 很高兴终于见到你
Mr. Reed, it's so nice to meet you, finally.
我们刚好在这个地区 想顺便拜访一下
We were just in the area, and we wanted to stop by
因为你提到你可能有兴趣
because you mentioned you might be interested
了解更多关于耶稣基督
in learning more about the Church of Jesus Christ
后期圣徒教会的信息
of Latter-day Saints?
是的
Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah.
里德先生 我们想给你这本小册子
Mr. Reed, we would like to give you this booklet,
因为它可以帮助你理解复兴
as it will help you understand the restoration.
我其实已经有一本了
I... I actually have one already,
但是  你永远不会嫌多
but, um, you can never have too many.
它告诉你所有的方式
It... it tells you all the ways
天父可以启示他的福音
the Heavenly Father can reveal His gospel.
- 作为他计划的一部分 - 谢谢
- As a part of His plan... - Thank you.
上帝拣选先知
...God chooses prophets,
例如亚当 挪亚 亚伯拉罕和摩西
such as Adam, Noah, Abraham and Moses.
-  先知 - 对 说到挪亚
- Uh, prophets... - Yeah, well, talking of Noah...
非常非常潮湿
...it is very, very wet.
教导关于上帝的事 并接受启示
...teach about God and receive revelation,
他们解释上帝的话语 并向世界传讲福音
and they interpret the word of God, and preach
由于叛教
the gospel to the world, and because of Apostasy...
你想进来吗
Would you like to come inside?
人们失去了对福音的认识
...people lose knowledge of the gospel.
你有女性室友吗
Do you have a girl roommate?
女性 什么
A girl, who?
室友
A... a roommate?
除非有另一位女性在场 否则我们不能进去
We can't come inside unless another woman is present
但是  我们可以  待在门口这里
but, um, we can, uh, stay out here
如果你不介意的话
in the doorway, if that's fine with you?
只是为了安全 我们不介意下雨
It's just for safety. We don't mind the rain.
我妻子在家 这算吗
Well, my wife is home. Does that count?
- 算 - 太好了
- Yeah! - Perfect.
当你说“室友”时 我慌了 我
When you said "roommate," I panicked. I...
自从  之后我就没有室友了
I haven't had a roommate since, uh...
总之 我有一个灵魂伴侣 这就够了
Anyway, I... I have a soulmate and that is good enough?
- 是的 - 太好了
- Yes! - That's great!
我们很乐意进来见见你的妻子
We'd love to come in and meet your wife.
那就进来吧 太好了
Then come on in! Great!
- 你喜欢派吗 - 喜欢
- Do you like pie? - Yeah!
我妻子在烤派
My wife has pie in the oven.
我在传教期间胖了很多
I've gained so much weight on my mission.
人们总是给我们好吃的
People are always feeding us treats.
我们似乎从来没有拒绝过
We never seem to turn them down.
我妻子喜欢烘焙
Well, my wife loves to bake.
- 我可以拿走你们的外套吗 - 哦 好的
- May I take your coats? - Oh, yes.
我真的很喜欢派 我非常兴奋
I really love pie. I'm super excited.
我奶奶以前做的派最好吃
My grandma used to make the best pie.
好吧 那你和我妻子会相处得很好
Okay, well, you and my wife are gonna get on very well.
- 太好了 - 哦 有一件事
- Great. - Oh, one thing,
墙壁和天花板里有金属
the walls and ceilings have metal in them.
- 我希望这没关系 - 我们不介意
- I hope that's okay. - We don't mind.
好的
Good!
那我去看看点心
Well, I will go and check on the snacks.
请自便
Make yourselves at home.
谢谢
Thank you.
我妻子很害羞
My wife is being shy.
但是派 派快好了
But the pie, the pie is nigh.
她也必须和我们一起待在房间里
She'll have to be in the room with us too.
是的 当然 对 我明白
Yes, of course! Of course, right. I understand.
请坐
Please take a seat, take a seat, take a seat.
几瓶可乐 请自便
Couple of colas. Help... help yourself.
我认为
I think...
信教是件好事
it is good to be religious.
那我们的工作就完成了
Well, our work here is done.
不 我只是想让你们在开始之前知道
No. I just want you to know that before we start.
是的 我想我们会认为
Yeah, I think that we would consider
听到这个消息很振奋
that refreshing to hear.
有时候 感觉好像
Well, sometimes, it feels like
宗教不再是文化的中心了
maybe religion isn't at the center of culture anymore.
它正在消退 不是吗
Well, it's fading, isn't it?
是的 随着时间的推移 嗯哼
Yeah, over time. Mm-hmm.
好的 你们准备好听听
Okay, are you ready to hear about
天父为你们制定的计划了吗
our Heavenly Father's plan for you?
我准备好了 等等
I am! Wait.
你们俩都是哪里人
Where are you both from?
我 来自犹他州奥格登
Me? Ogden, Utah.
八个女儿中的一个 我知道
One of eight daughters. I know,
这听起来很糟糕
it's as bad as it sounds.
巴恩斯姐妹来自盐湖城
And Sister Barnes is from Salt Lake City.
费城 原籍
Uh, Philadelphia, originally.
啊
Ah.
你们俩都是在教会里长大的 对吗
And you're both raised in the church, yeah?
土生土长
Born and raised.
我母亲是皈依者 所以
My mother was a convert, so, um,
当我父亲去世后
when my dad passed away,
我们试了几个不同的教会
we auditioned a few different churches,
只是想看看外面有什么
just to see what was out there
看看我们是否还相信它
and see if we still believed in it.
我懂那种感觉
I know that feeling.
我非常懂那种感觉
I know that feeling very well.
找到你真正相信的教义的信仰
It's so important to find your faith
这非常重要
in a doctrine you actually believe,
这是一个非常非常个人的挣扎
and that's a very, very personal struggle.
这是一个我挣扎了
That is a personal challenge that I have struggled with
很长很长时间的个人挑战
for a very, very long time.
你知道
You know,
什么是唯一真正的宗教
what is the one, true religion?
这很有趣 霍尔姐妹告诉我们
It's funny, Sister Hall was telling us
我们应该
that we should
优先考虑其他调查者
prioritize other investigators.
- 哦 - 哦 但是 不
- Oh. - Oh, but no! I...
我只是说
I'm just saying
我可以看出你
that I could tell that you
是一个对灵性非常好奇的人
are a very spiritually curious person,
就像约瑟·斯密一样
just like Joseph Smith.
你知道 约瑟调查了许多不同的教派
You know, Joseph investigated many different denominations,
长老会 卫理公会 天主教
Presbyterian, Methodist, Catholicism.
没有一个完全合适
And none of them quite fit,
这就是为什么约瑟创立了我们的教会
which is why Joseph founded our church.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
据我所知 别打断我
As I understand it, stop me when I go wrong,
他在夜里被一位名叫摩罗尼的天使拜访
he was visited in the night by an angel called Morony.
- 摩罗乃 - 摩罗乃 对
- Moroni. - Moroni. Yeah.
摩罗乃 他向他展示了在哪里可以找到
Moroni, who showed him where he could locate
他家附近的一些金页片
some golden plates near his home.
他对这些页片的神秘翻译
His mysterious translation of those plates
构成了这本书的基础
form the basis of this.
哇
Wow!
不 你读的比我们还多
No, you read more than we do!
不 说真的
No, seriously,
我们应该向你学习 里德先生
we should be more like you, Mr. Reed!
“阅读”先生
Mr. "Read."
派闻起来真香
The pie smells amazing.
既然你一直在学习摩门经
And now that you've been studying The Book of Mormon,
它让你有什么感觉
how does it make you feel?
你能猜到她在做什么派吗
Can you guess what kind of pie she's making?
是
Is it...
蓝莓派吗
blueberry pie?
是蓝莓派
It is blueberry pie!
是的 我就知道
Yes! I knew it!
我最喜欢的
My favorite!
回到刚才 我能问一下
Going back, can I ask
你父亲是怎么去世的吗
how did your father pass away?
- 嗯 - 对不起
- Um... - I'm sorry.
- 我不应该 - 卢伽雷氏症
- I shouldn't... - Lou Gehrig's disease.
蓝莓病
Blueberry disease?
好的 那
Okay, that's...
那 太好了 蓝莓病
That's... that's wonderful, blueberry disease.
谁不想要呢 是的
Who wouldn't want that? Yeah.
呃
Uh...
卢伽雷氏症
Lou Gehrig's disease.
伽雷氏
Gehrig's.
哦 那 太可怕了
Oh, that's... that's awful.
我很抱歉 我听错了
I'm so sorry. I... I... I misheard.
那是一种恶性疾病
That is a malicious affliction.
我以为你在开玩笑
I... I thought you were making a joke
关于派的玩笑 对不起
about the pie. I'm sorry.
是的
Yeah.
你父亲去世后 你有没有看到过他的迹象
Have you seen any signs of your father since he passed?
他有没有试图从另一边和你交流
Has he tried to communicate from the other side?
没有
Mmm, no.
奇怪
Strange.
好吧 我
Well, I'm...
我真的很抱歉 我对
I'm really sorry, and I'm sorry about the...
蓝莓的误会感到抱歉
blueberry mix-up.
没关系
It's okay.
当我死后 我想变成一只蝴蝶
When I die, I want to come back as a butterfly,
只是为了跟随我爱的人
just to follow around the people I love.
我会落在他们的手上
I'll land right on their hand.
不是他们的胳膊 不是他们的 头
Not their arm, not their... their head,
而是落在他们的指尖上 这样他们就知道是我
right on their fingertip, so they know it's me.
啊
Ah.
那很甜蜜
That's sweet.
哦
Oh!
抱歉 这是房子的一个小毛病
Apologies! That is a foible of the house.
对不起 它就是这样
I'm sorry. It does that. It does that.
好吧
Um, well...
女士们 我现在不能见你们了
Ladies, I can't see you now.
- 嗯 我想是时候了 - 嗯
- Um, I think it is time. - Hmm.
什么时间
Time for what?
吃派的时间
Time for pie!
派
Pie!
呜呼
Woohoo!
还有  启蒙的时间
And, uh, time for enlightenment.
哦
Oh?
对不起 我应该给你倒水的
I'm sorry, I should have offered you water.
智慧语禁止
The word of wisdom forbids
咖啡因和酒精 不是吗
caffeine and alcohol, doesn't it?
它没有  特别提到苏打水
Well, it doesn't, uh, specifically mention soda.
当然 避免含咖啡因的饮料可能更健康
Sure, it may be healthier to avoid caffeinated drinks,
但我们只是不渴
but we're just not thirsty.
啊哈
Aha.
你对尴尬的问题有什么看法
How do you feel about awkward questions?
那个表情包
The meme?
呵呵 不 我想问一个尴尬的
Heh, no. I want to ask an awkward, uh,
一个令人讨厌的问题
an icky question,
一个不敏感的问题 我认为
an insensitive question that I think
这会很快增加我们谈话的深度
will add depth to our conversation
在太阳落山之前
very quickly before the sun goes down
我们今晚就结束了
and we're done for the evening.
但前提是你觉得舒服
But only if you're comfortable with that.
我们不知道自己是否舒服
Well, we won't know if we're comfortable
- 直到你问 所以 - 有道理
- until you ask, so... - Fair point.
也许你直接问
Maybe you just ask?
好的
Okay.
如果你不问
If you don't ask,
我会离开这里 想知道我们错过了什么
I'm gonna leave here wondering what we missed out on.
很好 我的问题是
Very well. My question is this. Um...
现在我觉得它已经被渲染了
Now I feel it's been built up to. Uh...
我应该要求击鼓吗
Should I request a drum roll?
我要请求击鼓
I'm going to request a drum roll.
请击鼓 女士们
A drum roll please, ladies!
继续
Keep going! Keep going! Keep going!
更多
More! More! More!
现在 我的问题是
Now, I... I... I... my question is,
你对一夫多妻制有什么看法
how do you feel about polygamy?
你对一个男人有多个妻子
How do you... how do you feel about the concept of
的概念有什么看法
a man having multiple wives?
我的意思是 这不适合我
I mean, it's... it's not for me, um...
你是从圣经的角度问的吗
Are you asking from a biblical perspective?
摩门教有一段有争议的历史
Uh, Mormonism has a controversial history
与厌女行为有关
with the misogynist practice
男人拥有多个妻子
of men claiming multiple wives.
但我对现代启示的概念很着迷
But I am fascinated by the idea of Modern Revelation,
它被用来抹去这种行为
which was used to erase this behavior
从 1890 年的教会中
from the church in 1890.
我认为这值得讨论
I just think that's worthy of conversation.
是吗
Yeah? Uh...
我的意思是
And what I mean by that
我们正在讨论一个教会
is that we're discussing a church that
它认为有争议的做法
decided that a controversial practice
是其声誉上的污点 并且实际上阻碍了
was a stain on its reputation, and an actual hindrance
招募新成员 所以它使用了启示
to recruiting new members, and so it used revelation,
上帝对先知说的话
word of God told unto the prophet
来驱逐一个挑衅性的宗教支柱
to banish a provocative religious pillar
这在当代似乎令人反感
that seemed unsavory in contemporary times.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I know that, um,
这可能很难理解
it may be difficult to understand, um,
但是  一夫多妻制是一项精神使命
but, uh, polygamy was a spiritual mission
在当时是必要的
needed at the time in order
为了在经历了很多苦难和流血之后
to grow the ranks of our membership
增加我们的成员人数
in the wake of much hardship and bloodshed.
一个男人有多个妻子
Um... a man having plural wives
意味着更多 更多的婴儿来帮助社区发展
meant more... more babies to help the community grow.
嗯
Hmm.
是的 这对我们现代人的大脑来说
It's, yeah, it's sketch for sure,
- 肯定是粗略的 - 它被
- to our modern brains. - And it was...
从教会中移除 不仅仅是因为
it was removed from the church not just because
它很奇怪或有争议
it was grotesque or controversial,
只是因为它不再需要了
but just because it wasn't necessary anymore.
你看 我担心 并且
You see, I worry, and...
原谅我说话大声
forgive my loud language,
呃
uh,
我担心约瑟·斯密利用一夫多妻制的概念
I worry that Joseph Smith used the concept of polygamy
来使他与其他女人的婚外情合法化
to legitimize his affairs with other women.
我担心约瑟的妻子艾玛·斯密
I worry that Joseph's wife, Emma Smith,
当他和范妮·阿尔杰睡觉时 她很生气
was upset when he slept with Fanny Alger,
他们 16 岁的女仆
their sixteen-year-old maid.
我担心他制定了一个计划
I worry that he formulated a plan
在那次轻率行为之后
to use revelation for consequence-free sex
利用启示来进行无后果的性行为
in the aftermath of that indiscretion
以及其他类似的
and others like it.
你知道 “能力越大 责任越大”
You know, "With great power comes great responsibility."
蜘蛛侠
Spiderman.
伏尔泰
Voltaire.
对
Right.
我想向大家提出的是我的担忧
I guess what I would pose to the room is my concern
一夫多妻制没有任何精神意义
that polygamy has no spiritual bearing whatsoever.
我认为这有点扭曲
That is somewhat of a distortion, I think...
教会自己的历史证实
The church's own history corroborates
并暗示了这种
and implies this...
愤世嫉俗的洗脑策略
...cynical brainwashing tactic.
这是真的吗
Is that true?
我 对不起
I... I... I'm sorry,
我不知道你从哪里得到这些
I... I'm not sure where you're getting this.
如果上帝的启示是通过人过滤的
If revelation by God is filtered through man
而人是有缺陷的 人会犯罪 人会撒谎
and man is flawed and man sins and man lies,
那我们怎么知道这一切都是真的
then how do we know any of it's true?
我们知道这是真的 因为它给我们的感觉
We know it's true because of how it makes us feel.
宾果 说得对
Bingo! That's exactly right!
完全正确 完全同意
That's exactly right. Couldn't agree more.
重要的是我们与上帝的个人关系
It's our personal relationship with God which matters.
让我们和我们的主教谈谈
Let us talk with our bishop
你提出的一些观点
about some of the points you're raising. Um...
问题 你最喜欢的快餐是什么
Question. What's your favorite fast food?
我尽量不吃
I try not to eat it.
我们都不吃 但是 说吧 我们都有一个
None of us do, but go on, we've all got one.
嗯
Um...
好的 汉堡王比卡乐星好
Okay. Burger King is better than Carl's Junior...
什么是卡乐星
What's Carl's Junior?
东海岸的哈迪斯
Hardee's on the East Coast.
汉堡王比哈迪斯好
Burger King is better than Hardee's
哈迪斯比拉力好
which is better than Rally's...
- 拉力 - 切克斯
- Rally's? - Checkers.
汉堡王比
Burger King is better
哈迪斯好 哈迪斯比切克斯好
than Hardee's, which is better than Checkers,
切克斯比温蒂好 温蒂比 In-N-Out 好
which is better than Wendy's, which is better than In-N-Out,
In-N-Out 比麦当劳好
which is better than McDonalds,
麦当劳比盒子里的杰克好
which is better than Jack in the Box,
盒子里的杰克比什么都没有好
which is better than nothing.
盒子里的杰克全天供应早餐
Jack in the Box serves breakfast all day.
我喜欢早餐
I love breakfast!
塔可钟呢
What about Taco Bell?
我们不谈论塔可钟
We don't talk about Taco Bell.
为什么我们不谈论塔可钟
Why don't we talk about Taco Bell?
我们必须谈论塔可钟才能谈论
We'd have to talk about Taco Bell to talk about...
为什么我们不谈论塔可钟
why we don't talk about Taco Bell.
好吧 所以汉堡王是第一名
All right, so... so Burger King is number one.
- 我觉得它是垃圾 - 哦
- I think it's trash. - Oh.
对 不是盒子里的杰克
Right. Not Jack in the Box.
我投温蒂
I vote Wendy's.
我可以支持
I could support.
好的 温蒂就是它了 是的
Good! Wendy's it is. Yeah.
你知道吗 我从来没有吃过温蒂
Do you know? I've never had a Wendy.
我说错了
That came out wrong.
没关系
It's okay.
所以当我开始学习神学时
So when I started studying theology,
我最不想做的就是找到
the last thing I wanted to do was find...
宗教中的温蒂
the Wendy's of religions.
我只是在写一篇
I was just writing a research paper
大学课程的研究论文 我满足于涉猎
for a college class, and I was content with dabbling.
所以 这里吃点麦乐鸡 那里吃个汉堡王皇堡
So, some McNuggets here, BK Whopper over there,
随便什么心情
whatever fit the mood.
当我研究这些流派 麦当劳 汉堡王 In-N-Out
As I studied the genres, McD, BK, In-N-Out,
即 摩门教 山达基教 伊斯兰教 佛教
i.e., Mormonism, Scientology, Islam, Buddhism,
当我通过流派和
as I got closer to God
严格的研究更接近上帝时
through genre and rigorous study,
当我致力于我与天父的个人关系时
as I worked on my personal relationship
我想我加强了它
with Heavenly Father, and I think strengthened it,
你知道我发现了什么吗
do you know what I found?
你知道的越多 你知道的就越少
The more you know, the less you know.
当我 50 岁的时候 我营养不良
And by the time I was 50, I was malnourished
因为我一直在吃宗教快餐
from the fast food of religion I'd been packing into my brain
在过去十年的大部分时间里
for the best part of a decade.
每个教派 邪教 信条 教派
Every sect, cult, creed, denomination
都声称自己是唯一真正的教义
all claimed to be the one, true doctrine,
但在显微镜下观察时 似乎没有一个是真的
and yet none seemed true when held under the microscope.
所以我想知道还有什么
So I wondered what else was out there.
我向你保证
I promise you,
我最不想做的
the last thing I wanted to do
就是找到唯一真正的宗教
was find the one true religion.
但不幸的是 我找到了
But unfortunately, I did.
我们可以见见你的妻子吗
Can we meet your wife?
拜托
Please?
当然 可以
Of course, yes!
她只需要在场 我们也想
She just has to be present, and we want
- 也想见见她 - 是的
- to meet her as well. - Yeah.
抱歉 我去问问
Sorry. I'll... I'll go ask.
巴恩斯姐妹 我不知道
Sister Barnes, I don't... I don't know.
是的 我不想吓到他
Yeah, I don't want to spook him,
但我们应该结束了
but we should wrap this.
有什么消息吗
Any messages?
没有
Nothing.
好的
Okay. Um...
让我们礼貌地结束这个 然后回去
let's just politely wrap this and head back.
只是重点
Just the highlights...
她终于准备好了
And she is finally ready.
抱歉
Sorry about that.
进来吧 她很想 见你们
Come on through. She's eager to... meet you.
我们到了
There we are.
- 这边 - 好的
- This way. - Okay.
等一下 里德先生 我们刚接到
One moment, Mr. Reed. Uh, we're just getting a call
救济会会长的电话
from the Relief Society president.
- 我们马上就到 - 哦 你需要一分钟吗
- We'll be right there. - Oh, do you need a minute?
嗨
Hi.
- 这是巴恩斯姐妹  - 我等着
- This is Sister Barnes. Um... - I'll wait.
- 我在另一边等着 - 是的 等一下
- I'll wait on the other side. - Yeah. Just one moment.
- 谢谢 - 是的
- Thank you. - Yeah.
- 我们应该离开吗 - 现在
- Should we leave? - Now?
- 是吗 - 是的
- Yeah? - Yes? Yes.
什么事
What is it?
我们的自行车
Our bikes.
是吗
Yeah?
它们锁在外面
They're locked outside.
那又怎样
So what?
他拿着我们的外套
He has our coats.
自行车锁的钥匙在我外套口袋里
The key to the bike lock is in my coat pocket.
所以我们需要我们的外套
So we need our coats.
是的
Yeah.
- 我们需要 - 我不知道 我们需要吗
- We do. - I don't know, do we?
不穿外套 不骑自行车走回去
Walk back without coats and bikes?
那有多远 两英里
What is that, two miles?
不 我觉得是四英里
No, I think it's four.
这有点过分 但是 我
It's a little over the top, but I...
我没事 我可以走 是吗
I'm fine. I'm fine to walk, yeah?
- 卡住了 - 解锁
- It's stuck. - Unlock it.
没有 锁
There's no... lock.
什么 用力拉
What? Pull harder.
这里
Here. Here.
好的
All right.
他还在吗
Is he still there?
我们不是听到他走了吗
Didn't we hear him leave?
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我们应该向他求助吗
Should we ask him for help?
不
No.
你能从这里钻过去吗
Can you fit through this?
你疯了吗
You crazy?
我们应该试试霍尔姐妹 好吗
Um, we should try Sister Hall, okay?
或者肯尼迪长老 只是让他们知道我们在哪里
Or Elder Kennedy, just so they know where we are.
没有回应
It's not going through.
是暴风雨 继续尝试 好吗
It's the storm. Keep trying, okay?
好的
Okay.
我们寻求帮助
We ask for help, hmm?
会没事的
It'll be fine.
里德先生
Mr. Reed?
他们来了 欢迎
And there they are! Welcome.
里德先生 你太慷慨了
Mr. Reed, you have been too generous with your time.
帕克斯顿姐妹和我刚才还在说
Sister Paxton and I were just saying
这是一件多么愉快的事
what a pleasure it's been.
但是我们刚和霍尔姐妹通完电话
Um, but we just got off the phone with Sister Hall,
她需要我们回到教会
and she needs us to return to the church.
- 哦 好吧 - 不幸的是 是的
- Oh! Oh, well... - Unfortunately, yeah.
如果你想离开 我不会留你
I won't keep you if you wish to leave.
我们被召回了
We've been summoned back.
是的
Yeah.
该死的 因为我们才
Damn it! Damn it, 'cause we were just
刚刚开始 不是吗
getting started, weren't we?
你知道 你让我觉得也许你
You know, you had me thinking that maybe you were
的拜访有什么意义
onto something with your visit.
我印象深刻 但我理解
I've been impressed, but I understand.
是的 你的外套在这里
Uh, yeah, your coats are here,
挂在长椅后面
hanging on the back of the pew.
请稍等一下
Excuse me one moment.
是的
Yeah.
钥匙
Key.
所以我们只是  需要你的帮助
So... so we just, uh, need your help
开门
with the door. Um...
它有点棘手
It's... it's a little tricky.
对不起
I'm sorry?
我想你的门在那里有点卡住了
I think your door is a bit stuck out there.
门打不开
The door won't open.
前门
The front door.
是的 前门又打不开了
Yeah, the front door won't open again.
我们进来的时候它打开了
It opened when we came in.
是的
Yeah.
也许如果你解锁 它就会打开
Maybe if you unlock it, it will open?
不 我明白你在问我什么
No, no, I... I... I understand what you're asking me,
但是
but, uh,
门闩是定时的
the deadbolts are on a timer.
我和你们的谈话太投入了
I got carried away with our conversation,
我没有意识到支架已经设置好了
I didn't realize the brace had been set.
你们进来的时候我应该拔掉销子的
I should have pulled the pin when you came in,
但我忘了 所以如果你现在
but I forgot. So if you are now
遗憾地准备离开
regrettably ready to leave,
你必须从我家后面出去
you'll have to exit through the back of my house.
哪里
Uh, where?
就在这里
Just through here.
好吧 你能把前面的那个解锁吗 拜托
Well, can you just unlock the front one, please?
我们想走那边
We would like to go that way.
这样我们出去的时候
Just so we don't get turned around
就不会迷路
and confused when we get outside.
是的 它要到早上才会再打开
Yeah, it won't open again 'til morning.
拜托 先生
Please, sir?
哦 对不起
Oh, I'm sorry.
我向你保证 这样离开是安全的
I promise you, it's safe to leave this way.
嗯
Huh?
有一扇门
It's a little unusual to have a door
定时上锁 这有点不寻常
that, um, locks on a timer?
呃
Uh...
是的 我知道
Yes, well, I see that.
是的
Yeah.
而且它
And it's...
好吧 它不能解锁 这有点不寻常
Well, it's a little unusual that it can't be unlocked.
不 我知道
No, I... I... I know.
我有足够的自知之明 知道这可能是什么样子
I am self-aware enough to know how this might look.
一个老人 两个年轻女子在他家里
Older man, two young women in his house,
但我向你保证 你可以随意离开
but I assure you, you are welcome to leave
从后面
through... through the back.
你从外面看到我的房子了 对吧
You saw my house from the outside, right?
- 嗯哼 - 对
- Mm-hmm. - Right!
所以 你知道它占地面积很小
So, you know it's a tiny footprint.
房子的后面就在那里
The back of the house is just there.
是的
Yeah.
总之 我会给你空间让你自由地做出决定
Anyway, I will leave you space to make your decision freely.
是的
Yeah.
澄清一下 我正在努力
To clarify, I am trying...
一直努力做到
have been trying very hard to make it a point
不给你施加压力
not to pressure you,
所以你甚至不应该觉得有必要
so you shouldn't even feel the need
编造一个关于你病房里的人的故事
to fabricate a story about someone from your ward
打电话让你离开 这 完全没问题
calling you to leave. It's... perfectly fine.
你想什么时候离开就什么时候离开
Leave when you want.
这不是借口 他们确实需要我们回去
It wasn't an excuse, they do need us back.
不 我知道 但你说你接了一个电话
No, I know, but you're saying you took a call
和你病房里的人打的电话
with someone from your ward.
是的 刚才
Yeah, a moment ago.
但是当你进来的时候 我问你是否可以接受
But when you came inside, I asked if you were okay
墙壁和天花板上的金属
with the metal in the walls and ceilings.
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
我的意思是金属会阻碍手机信号
I mean that the metal obstructs cell phone signals,
所以我知道你没有接电话 但是
so I do know you didn't take a call. But...
只是为了清楚起见
Just to be clear,
所以你很舒服
so you're comfortable,
你完全可以自行离开
it is totally fine for you to leave on your own accord.
你永远不需要觉得你必须
You never need to feel like you have to...
找借口 或者告诉我一些
...make excuses or... or tell me little...
一些 小谎言
little... little white lies.
所以哪扇门通向外面
So which door takes us outside?
噗
Pff.
好吧 你有偏好吗
Well... do you have a preference?
什 为什么我会有偏好
Wh... why would I have a preference?
我们应该有偏好吗
Should we have a preference?
这是一个公平的问题
That is a fair question.
不是完全奇怪 但是你的妻子能不能
Not to be completely weird, but can your wife
请走进房间
please just step in the room,
打个招呼 然后带我们去房子的后面
say hello and walk us to the back of the house?
我不是想装傻
I'm not trying to be silly,
我保证 我真的不是
I promise, I'm really not,
但是我们遵循规则 我们对它们很坦诚
but there are rules we follow, and we were upfront with them.
我会问的
I will ask.
我可以先问你一个问题吗
Can I ask you a question first?
你
Do you...
你还相信我的妻子在隔壁房间吗
still believe that my wife is in the next room?
尽管有相反的证据
Despite all the evidence to the contrary,
香薰蜡烛
the scented candle,
没有烤箱和蓝莓派
the absence of an oven with blueberry pie?
或者你一直在礼貌地纵容一个谎言
Or have you been politely indulging a lie?
如果你仍然相信她在那里 我会去问
If you still believe that she's in there, I'll go ask,
但这是我想让你思考的事情
but it's something I want you to think about
也许思考一下
and maybe think about
在你的信仰背景下
in the context of your beliefs.
你相信上帝是因为
Do you believe in God because
有人在你易受影响的年龄告诉你
somebody told you at an impressionable age
上帝是真实的 尽管你长大后
that God is real, despite having doubts
有疑问 尽管
as you got older, despite...
一生中都看到了相反的证据
seeing evidence to the contrary your whole lives?
当你父亲失去对身体的控制时
When your father lost control of his body,
你认为这是上帝的计划要毁了他的生活吗
did you think it was God's plan to ruin his life?
或者你继续相信一些东西
Or did you go on believing something
你知道那不是真的 只是为了给你安慰
that you know is not true just to give you comfort
因为你害怕如果这一切都是谎言
because you were afraid of what it might mean
那意味着什么
if it was all a lie?
我把香薰蜡烛放在桌子上
I put the scented candle on the table
因为我想让你思考
because I wanted you to think
你相信的事情
about the things that you believe
只是因为有人让你相信它们
just because somebody asked you to believe them.
可以
Can...
我们可以用你的电话吗
Can we use your phone?
拜托
Please?
我没有电话
I... I don't have a telephone.
你有一个非常漂亮的家 里德先生
You have a really beautiful home, Mr. Reed.
这里就像一座教堂
It's like a church in here.
你自己建造的吗
Did you build it yourself?
我妻子建造的
My wife built it.
我们要离开
We're gonna leave
从你家后面
through the back of your house.
现在 可以吗
Now, is that okay?
当然
Of course.
就像你说的 没关系
Just like you said, it's okay,
我们可以离开 对吧
and we can leave, right?
没错
That's right.
什么事
What is it?
巴恩斯姐妹
Sister Barnes?
那是地下室
That's a basement.
看起来这不通向外面
It doesn't look like this goes outside.
我想你可以看出我们对今晚的情况
I think that you can tell that we're regrettably
感到遗憾地不舒服
uncomfortable with this situation here tonight.
对不起 但你刚才不是说
I'm sorry, but didn't you just say a moment ago
你看到我房子的外面了吗
that you saw the outside of my house?
所以你清楚地看到了
So then you clearly saw...
我房子的后面悬在一座小山上
...that the back of my house overhangs a hill,
所以你会知道你必须下去
so you would know that you have to go down...
才能出去
...in order to go out.
我认为对你来说最好
I think it would be best for you
对我们所有人来说 如果你能帮助我们
and for all of us if you could help us
回家 因为
go home because
支联会会长 他知道我们在哪里
the Stake President, he knows where we are.
病房传教士也知道
And the Ward Missionaries know.
他们会等着我们
And they'll be expecting us.
还有目击者 不是吗 巴恩斯姐妹
And there were witnesses, weren't there, Sister Barnes?
在来这里的路上 我们经过了一名警官
On our way here, we passed a police officer?
哇 警察 我向你保证
Whoa! The police? I promise you,
你太 太激动了
you're getting way, way, way, way too worked up.
对
Right.
但我认为我们害怕
But I think that we're scared
因为你早些时候对我们撒谎了
because you lied to us earlier.
你想让我帮忙吗
Do you want me to help?
你早些时候问我是否应该
You asked me earlier if you should
在门之间有偏好
have a preference between the doors.
我认为你应该 我认为这是你应该考虑的事情
I think you should. I think it's something
非常仔细地
you should consider very carefully,
然后做出正确的决定
and then make the right decision.
你想让我帮你吗
Do you want me to help you?
是的
Yes.
好的
Okay.
那么 请
Then, please...
过来站在这里 你们俩都过来
come and stand here. Both of you come.
就在这里
Just here.
就这样
That's it.
这是一个简单的选择
It's a simple choice.
但不应该简单地做出
But it should not be made simply.
我需要你非常非常深入地反思
I need you to reflect very, very deeply
然后做出一个真诚的决定
and then make a sincere decision.
你玩过吗
Have you ever played
帕克兄弟的游戏 《大富翁》
the Parker Brothers game,  Monopoly?
《大富翁》目前以 47 种语言出版
Monopoly  is currently published in 47 languages.
他们在超过 114 个国家销售它
They sell it in over 114 countries.
♪ 如果我能许个愿 ♪
♪ If I could make a wish ♪
他们说有超过 10 亿人玩过《大富翁》
They say over a billion people have played Monopoly.
但我猜只有那一小部分人
But I'm guessing that only a fraction of that billion
实际上完成了它
have actually finished it.
也许这让你想起了
Maybe that reminds you
别的东西
of something else?
只是一个想法
Just a thought.
这是大多数人听到“大富翁”时的意思
This is what most people mean when they hear  "Monopoly."
有锡制头像
There's the pewter avatars.
每个人都有自己喜欢的 我不会告诉你我的
Everyone has their favorite. I shall not tell you mine.
喵
Meow!
有各种面额的彩色钞票
There's the pastel money in various denominations,
当然 还有监狱
and, of course, the jail.
现在 接下来的部分非常重要
Now, this next part is very important.
你玩过 1904 年的棋盘游戏吗
Have you ever played the 1904 board game called
叫《地主的游戏》
The Landlord's Game?
它几乎与《大富翁》相同
It is very nearly identical to  Monopoly
在每一个基本方面 都有监狱
in every fundamental way. There's the jail.
有免费停车场
There's free parking.
有罚款和费用 有处罚
There's fines and fees. There's penalties.
因为落在别人的财产上
for landing on other people's properties,
以及形成垄断的最终目标
and the ultimate goal of forming monopolies
迫使你的对手退出游戏
to force your opponent out of the game.
游戏和我们离开有什么关系
What do games have to do with us leaving?
一切
Everything.
《地主的游戏》是由
The Landlord's Game  was designed by
美国女权主义者伊丽莎白·玛吉设计的
American feminist Elizabeth Magie,
比一位来自费城的
almost three decades before
加热器推销员早了近三十年
a heater salesman from Philadelphia,
巴恩斯姐妹 将名字改为《大富翁》
Sister Barnes, changed the name to Monopoly
并在 1935 年
and sold the concept as his own
将这个概念作为他自己的
to Parker Brothers in 1935.
卖给了帕克兄弟
This chap was called Charles Darrow,
这家伙叫查尔斯·达罗
went on to become the first millionaire games designer
后来成为世界上第一位百万富翁游戏设计师
in the history of the world, while poor old Elizabeth Magie
在世界历史上 而可怜的老伊丽莎白·玛吉
died without ever being credited for the impact
去世时从未因其对美国文化的影响而受到赞誉
she had on American culture.
我在和你谈论
I'm talking to you
迭代
about iterations.
我需要你对迭代有一个非常基本的了解
I need you to have a very basic understanding
因为今晚我要
of iterating, because I'm going to make
做一个非常令人不安的声明
a very disturbing claim tonight.
它会让你的胃有点下沉
It will make your stomachs sink a little
你的心跳加快
and your hearts beat faster.
它会让你恶心
It will make you sick.
它甚至可能 我很抱歉
It may even... I'm very sorry...
让你想 去死
make you want to... to die.
你以前听过这首歌吗
Have you heard this song before?
你刚刚播放过
You just played it.
不 我是说今晚之前
No, I mean before tonight.
嗯嗯
Mmm-mmm.
我不同意
I disagree!
我想你以前听过很多很多次
I think you've heard it many, many times before,
但我们会回过头来谈
but we will come back to that.
你不是 一神论者吗
You are, are you not, monotheistic?
我们相信天父 是的
We believe in Heavenly Father, yes.
好的
Okay.
有三大一神论宗教
There are three major monotheistic religions,
犹太教 基督教和伊斯兰教
Judaism, Christianity and Islam.
我称它们为“三巨头”
I call them, "The Big Three."
犹太教 即
Judaism, i.e.
“原始版”
"The Original Edition."
基督教 即“最受欢迎版”
Christianity, i.e. "The Most Popular Edition,"
和伊斯兰教 “较新的
and Islam, "The Newer,
“第二受欢迎版”
"Second Most Popular Edition."
我可以看看你的摩门经吗 拜托
May I see your Book of Mormon, please?
我会还给你的
I'll give it back.
谢谢
Thank you.
最后 800 年后 这个
And finally, after 800 years, this!
摩门教 即
Mormonism, i.e.
“滑稽的地区衍生版”
"The zany regional spin-off edition."
这些都是相同源材料的迭代
These are all iterations
这些文本共享
of the same source material.
许多相同的字符
These texts share many of the same characters
和历史 尽管呈现
and histories albeit presented
具有不同的含义和观点
with different meanings and perspectives.
所以 不
So no,
我不会接受 你站在那里
I will not accept... ...that you stand there
告诉我你从来没有听过
and tell me that you've never heard
霍利斯乐队的《我呼吸的空气》
The Air That I Breathe  by The Hollies,
当我知道你听过电台司令乐队的《爬行》时
when I know that you have heard  Creep  by Radiohead.
哦 是的 你听过 来吧
Oh, yes, you have. Come on.
♪ 但我是一个爬虫 ♪
♪ But I'm a creep! ♪
是吗
Yeah?
♪ 我是一个怪人 ♪
♪ I'm a weirdo ♪
好的 “我到底在这里做什么”
Okay! "What the hell am I doing here?"
我知道这些是你现在正在思考的事情
I know these are things you are thinking right now,
但它们也是你认识的歌词 对吗
but they're also lyrics you recognize, yes?
对吗
Yes?
霍利斯乐队对电台司令乐队提起了剽窃诉讼
The Hollies filed a plagiarism lawsuit against Radiohead,
他们后来通过证明解决了这个问题
which they later settled by proving
《我呼吸的空气》的旋律和节奏
that the melody and rhythm of  The Air That I Breathe
出现在《爬行》中
appear in  Creep.
你多大了 19 岁还是 20 岁
How old are you? 19 or 20?
- 差不多 好的 - 嗯
- Something like that. Okay. - Hmm.
所以也许你认识拉娜·德雷
So maybe you know Lana Del Rey,
她非常了不起地被电台司令乐队起诉
who remarkably was sued by Radiohead
因为她在 2017 年的歌曲中剽窃了《爬行》
for plagiarizing  Creep  in her 2017 song
《获得自由》
Get Free.
迭代
Iterations.
随着时间的推移
Over time.
稀释信息
Diluting the message.
掩盖原作
Obscuring the original.
犹太教是原始的一神论宗教
Judaism is the OG monotheistic religion.
按理说 它应该
It should, by a wide margin,
拥有最多的实践成员 然而
have the most number of practicing members. And yet,
它只占世界人口的 0.2%
it makes up only 0.2% of the world's population.
为什么会这样
Why is that?
为什么原作不如
Why is the original less popular
迭代受欢迎
than the iteration?
它是否比其他宗教更不真实
Is it any less true than the others?
我们是在谈论宗教 棋盘游戏还是音乐
Are we talking about religion or board games or music?
是的
Yes.
它的成员最少 因为它不做广告
It has the fewest members because it doesn't advertise.
它没有像你这样的人
It doesn't have people like you,
敲门
knocking on doors,
向人们推销更好的生活
selling people a better life,
更好的棋盘游戏 更好的歌曲
a better board game, a better song.
你有没有想过
You ever think about that?
传教士实际上只是一个组织的
How missionaries are really just salespeople
销售人员
for an organization?
你销售的产品是一个想法
The product you're selling is an idea.
你敲我的门 你推销
You knock on my door and you sell,
也许我买 也许我不买
maybe I buy, maybe I don't buy.
当我邀请你进入我家时
Those are the rules of engagement
这些是交战规则
when I invite you into my house.
我们正在协商意识形态的交易
We are negotiating a transaction of ideologies.
我今晚想对你说的是
And what I'm trying to say to you tonight
我有一个想法 我想卖给你
is that I have an idea which I would like to sell to you.
我的论点是 神圣的文本
My argument is that the holy texts
我们所崇敬的
which we revere
只是古代人一直在
are just mythological iterations of stories
讲述的神话故事的迭代
which ancient people have been
几个世纪以来
telling each other for centuries.
它们在任何字面意义上都不是真实的或真实的
They're not true or real in any literal sense.
它们只是通往更古老真理的管道
They are merely a conduit to a more ancient truth.
救世主的故事
The story of a savior...
他由处女所生
who was born to a virgin,
他可以创造奇迹
who could perform miracles
并且超自然地复活了
and was supernaturally resurrected,
是一个非常受欢迎的故事
was a very popular story
至少在耶稣出生
for at least a thousand years
前一千年
before Jesus was born.
其中一个有金发
One of them has blonde hair,
其中一个是黑发 两者穿着相似
one of them's brunette, both dressed similar.
不 从未停下来
No. Never stopped by.
密特拉创造了奇迹
Mithras performed miracles.
他被十字架的标志所标记
He was marked by the sign of the cross.
荷鲁斯 在水上行走
Horus, walked on water,
被钉在十字架上 有 12 个门徒
was crucified, had 12 disciples.
克里希纳 他是一个木匠 由处女所生
Krishna, he was a carpenter, born to a virgin,
在河里受洗 从死里复活
baptized in a river, rose from the dead
并升入天堂
and ascended into heaven.
这个小画廊描绘了 12 位神
This little gallery depicts 12 gods
他们都出生在 12 月 25 日
who were born on December the 25th,
所有这些都早于耶稣的存在
all of whom predate the existence of Jesus.
我很抱歉
I am sorry,
但不可能忽视一个叙述
but it is impossible to ignore the influence
对另一个叙述的影响
of one narrative upon another,
或者忽视所有这些故事
or to ignore the fact that all these stories
迭代成
iterate into...
《星球大战：第一集 - 幽灵的威胁》
Star Wars: Episode I - The Phantom Menace.
你能想象几千年后
Can you imagine thousands of years from now
人们接受加·加
people accepting Jar Jar
作为一个重要的宗教人物吗
as a significant religious figure?
你说什么
Beg your pardon?
加·加 加·宾克斯
Jar Jar. Jar Jar Binks.
加·加 打扰一下
Jar Jar! Ex-squeeze me.
没关系
Never mind.
这一切都很可怕 不是吗 对不起
It is all terrifying, isn't it? I'm sorry.
是的
It is.
这一切都
It is all...
可怕
Scary.
我很害怕
I'm scared.
只是大声说出来 真的
I'm scared just saying it out loud, really.
如果上帝是真的 他会在我们自慰时看着我们
If God is real, and he watches when we masturbate,
他的自尊心如此脆弱 以至于他只在
and he has such a fragile ego that he only helps us
我们乞求他时才帮助我们 并向他献上赞美
when we beg him and shower him with praise,
他讨厌同性恋者
and he hates gay people
因为他让他们成为同性恋者
for being what he made them to be,
那太可怕了
well, that's terrifying.
如果没有上帝
If there's no God
我们只是好色的 微小的蚂蚁
and we're just horny, microscopic ants
漂浮在太空中的一块岩石上
floating on a rock through space
没有神圣的目的
with no divine purpose
也没有希望获得永生
and no hope to achieve eternal life,
那
well...
那也很可怕
that's terrifying too.
“要么教会是真的 要么它是一个骗局”
"Either the church is true or it is a fraud."
“它是上帝的教会和国度
"It is the church and kingdom of God,
“要么它什么都不是”
"or it is nothing."
你同意吗
Do you agree with that?
如果我告诉你这是戈登·辛克利
Would it help if I told you this is Gordon B. Hinckley,
你们教会的第 15 任会长
the 15th President of your church.
- 你同意戈登的观点吗 - 是的
- Do you agree with Gordon? - Yes.
- 嗯哼 - 我想也是
- Mm-hmm. - Thought you might.
所以要么这一切都是真的
So either it is all true
要么这一切都不是真的 对吗
or none of it's true, yes?
- 是的 - 嗯哼
- Yes. - Mm-hmm.
好的
Okay.
那我想让你选择走哪扇门
Then I want you to choose which door
根据你的信仰
to go through based on your faith.
是
Are...
你是要我们
are you asking us
审议我们对教会的信仰吗
for us to deliberate our belief in the church?
这是一个与我们回家
Is that a factor which will correspond
相对应的因素吗
to us going home?
我要求你在信仰和不信仰之间做出选择
I'm asking you to choose between belief, and disbelief.
我自己的主张是 世界上现存的 10000 种
My own claim is that all 10,000 verifiable religions
可验证的宗教
that exist in the world today
都和你们现在所处的
are as artificial as the symbolic church
象征性教堂一样虚假
you are currently standing in.
这是一场闹剧
It is farce.
这里没有神圣的东西
There is nothing holy here.
你们的宗教文本只是装饰品
Your religious text is mere ornament...
空洞而资本主义
...as hollow and as capitalistic
就像这些荒谬的游戏一样
as these ridiculous games.
我想知道我们会发生什么
I want to know what is going to happen to us
- 在我们选择之前 - 我甚至不知道
- before we choose. - I don't even know
如果还没有发生
how to begin to answer that question
我该如何回答这个问题
if it hasn't happened yet.
哇 里德先生
Wow, Mr. Reed,
你提出了很多有趣的观点
you've introduced a lot of interesting points.
我想我们可以承认你是一个非常聪明的人
I think we can admit that you're a very smart man
我们还有很多东西要学
and we still have a lot to learn.
因此 我想同意
So with that, I would like to agree
你已经
that you've...
说服了我们
convinced us,
我们想离开
and we'd like to leave
穿过不信仰之门 现在就回家
through the disbelief door and go home now.
对吧 巴恩斯姐妹
Right, Sister Barnes?
姐妹
Sister?
巴恩斯姐妹
Sister Barnes?
我想我们应该听听我们超级整洁
I think we should listen to our super neat
和体贴的主人的话 选择正确的门
and thoughtful host and choose the right door?
你知道 选择“正确的”
You know, choose the "right"?
就像他们在初级会教我们的那样
Like they taught us in primary?
这不
It doesn't...
不管你对他说什么
matter what you say to him.
他不会让我们走
He's not gonna let us go
只是因为我们承认他是对的
just because we admit he's right.
让我们趁我们的主人好心让
Let's just get out of here while our host is being
我们离开的时候离开这里
gracious enough to let us leave.
我认为我们正在被研究
I think that we're being studied.
我认为他想根据我们打开哪扇门
I think he wants to learn something about us
来了解我们的一些情况
based on which door we open.
这就是游戏吗
Is that the game?
有人挠了挠脖子 他在看
Someone scratches their neck, and he's watching.
我们说错了话 他结结巴巴地说不出话来
We say the wrong thing, and he stumbles on his words.
烛焰闪烁 捕捉了他的注意力
A candle flame flickers, and it captures his attention.
你一直在寻找什么
What have you been looking for?
你发现了什么
What have you found?
如果我是对的
If I'm right,
那么现在唯一重要的是
then the only thing that matters right now
我们真正相信什么
is what we actually believe.
因为我认为你的言辞很单薄
And because I think your rhetoric is thin,
你把旧货市场的棋盘游戏比作
and your garage sale board game metaphor
有点冒犯
is kind of offensive.
我的意思是 你问为什么犹太教只占
I mean, you asked why Judaism only makes up
世界人口的 0.2%
0.2% of the world's population
但甚至没有停下来谈论大屠杀
but didn't even pause for the Holocaust.
你没有承认犹太人面临的
You make no acknowledgement of the religious persecution
宗教迫害
Jewish people have faced.
你只是把它当作一个
You just use it as a setup
关于传教士的笑话的铺垫
to a punchline about missionaries.
然后 你跳过了这样一个事实
And then, you skip over the fact
所有这些都没有提到伊斯兰教
that none of this addresses Islam,
因为穆斯林甚至不相信基督复活了
as Muslims don't even believe Christ was resurrected.
然后 你指出了所有这些神话中的神
And then, you point out all the similarities
与耶稣的相似之处
these mythological gods have with Jesus,
但忽略了许多明显的差异
but breeze over the many glaring differences!
其中一个家伙有一个该死的鸟头
One of these guys has a freaking bird head!
我不认为 我的观点
I don't think... that my point of view...
符合信仰或不信仰
fits into belief or disbelief.
我认为有一个完整的频谱
I think there's an entire spectrum
你的游戏忽略了
that your game is neglecting.
所以这与我信不信无关 对吗
So it doesn't matter what I believe, does it?
帕克斯顿姐妹 你还相信上帝吗
Sister Paxton, do you still believe in God?
是的
Yes.
那我们从这里离开
Then let's leave through here.
让我们诚实和真诚
Let's be honest and sincere
让上帝决定我们接下来会发生什么
and let God decide what happens next for us.
好的 我们现在要离开了
Okay, we're leaving now.
感谢你所有的指导
Thank you for all your mentorship,
感谢你让我们离开
and thank you for letting us leave.
你也要来吗
Are you coming too?
姐妹
Sister...
没关系
It's okay.
一步一步来 我们慢慢走
One step at a time. We'll go slow.
巴恩斯姐妹 什么都没有
Sister Barnes, there's nothing.
都被挡住了
It's all blocked off.
你觉得他想要什么
What do you think he wants?
他会把我们永远关在这里吗
Is he gonna keep us here forever?
不 他太聪明了 他
No, he's too smart. He...
他知道长老会来找我们
He knows an Elder will check on us, and...
这意味着他要么必须让我们走 要么
which means he'll either have to let us go or...
杀了我们
kill us.
从现在开始 如果他提出了一个
From now on, if he lands a philosophical point
我们不同意的哲学观点 我们就挑战他
that we don't agree with, we challenge him.
我们让他思考
We make him think.
他不必压倒我们
He doesn't have to steam roll us.
我们可能不是身体上的威胁
We might not be a physical threat,
但我们可以成为智力上的威胁
but we can be an intellectual one.
我认为那扇窗户上有一个笼子
I think that window has a cage on it.
你说得对
You're right.
他来了
He's coming. He's coming.
拿着这个
Take this.
拿着这个 放回去
Take this. Put it back.
如果发生任何事情 你就拿着这个
If anything happens, you take this,
用尽全力
and you stab him in the neck as hard
尽快地刺他的脖子
and as fast as you can.
- 不 - 必须是你
- No! No, no! - It has to be you.
他太注意我了
He's watching me too closely.
- 他不会想到我们会这么做 - 姐妹 不
- He won't expect us to do it. - Sister, no!
好的 我们定一个暗号
Okay. Let's have a code word.
好吗 嗯
Okay? Um...
嘿 如果我说“魔法内衣”
Hey, if I say "magic underwear,"
那就意味着刺 好吗
that means stab. Okay?
他来了
He's coming.
魔法内衣 这是暗号 好吗
Magic underwear. That's the code word. Okay?
里德先生
Mr. Reed?
里德夫人
Mrs. Reed?
是你吗
Is that you?
她怎么了
What's happening to her?
♪ 但我是一个爬虫 ♪
♪ But I'm a creep
♪ 我是一个怪人 ♪
♪ I'm a weirdo
里德先生
Mr. Reed?
你在哪里
Where are you?
♪ 无法直视你的眼睛 ♪
♪ Couldn't look you in the eye ♪
♪ 你就像一个天使 ♪
♪ You're just like an angel
♪ 你的皮肤让我哭泣 ♪
♪ Your skin makes me cry
不
No.
♪ 我是一个爬虫 ♪
♪ And I'm a creep
♪ 我想控制 ♪
♪ I wanna have control
♪ 我想要一个完美的身体 ♪
♪ I want a perfect body
♪ 我想要一个完美的灵魂 ♪
♪ I want a perfect soul
♪ 我想让你注意到 ♪
♪ I want you to notice
♪ 当我不在身边时 ♪
♪ When I'm not around
♪ 你是如此特别 ♪
♪ You're so very special ♪
♪ 但我是一个爬虫 ♪
♪ But I'm a creep ♪
♪ 我是一个怪人 ♪
♪ I'm a weirdo
♪ 我到底在这里做什么 ♪
♪ What the hell am I doin' here? ♪
♪ 我不属于这里 ♪
♪ I don't belong here ♪
在我把你介绍给她之前
I had to be sure
我必须确定
before I introduced you to her.
确定什么
Sure about what?
你现在正站在一位
You are now in the presence
活着的上帝先知面前
of a living prophet of God.
我今晚邀请你进入
The reason I invited you
我的圣殿的原因是
into my sanctuary tonight is because
我看到了一个奇迹
I have been shown a miracle.
我相信这个奇迹证明
I believe this miracle is proof
所有已知的宗教都是明显错误的
that all known religions are demonstrably false,
只是对某种真实事物的古老回声
and only an ancient echo of something true.
我需要一个见证人
I need a witness,
你 来验证这个奇迹是真的
you, to verify that the miracle is real.
现在 我们家的蓝莓派食谱是
Now, our family recipe for blueberry pie is,
我认为 是一个传统的食谱
I think, a traditional one.
配料包括黄油 面粉 玉米淀粉
The ingredients include butter, flour, corn starch,
糖 柠檬
sugar, lemon,
当然还有蓝莓
blueberries, of course,
但今晚我还加了一些附子草
but tonight I've also included some wolf's bane
和颠茄
and some belladonna,
这意味着 不久之后
which means that, in a short while,
先知会因为吃了派而死去
the Prophet will be dead from consuming the pie.
然后
Then,
你将见证一个奇迹
you will witness a miracle.
在上帝的恩典下
By the grace of God,
她会复活
she will be resurrected.
现在 请感受她的脉搏
Now, feel her pulse, please.
你们俩都
Both of you.
我需要你
I need you
现在感受她的脉搏
to feel her pulse right now!
请承认
Acknowledge, please,
她的心脏现在已经停止跳动
that her heart has now stopped pumping.
你知道怎么做吗
Do you know how to do that?
食指和中指放在脖子的一侧
Index and middle finger on the side of the neck,
在气管旁边的柔软空心区域
in the soft, hollow area just beside the windpipe.
你们俩都 请抬起她的头以确保
Both of you, please, lift her head to be sure.
她动了
She moved! She moved!
那只是一次催化痉挛
That was just a catalytic spasm.
她还活着
She's alive!
不 还没有
No! No, no. Not yet.
化学物质被释放到她的体内
Chemicals being released into her body.
请承认 没有脉搏
Acknowledge, please, that there's no pulse.
承认
Acknowledge!
- 没有脉搏 - 没有脉搏
- No. No pulse. - No pulse.
谢谢
Thank you.
承认她不再呼吸了
Acknowledge that she is no longer breathing.
你感觉到呼吸了吗
Do you feel a breath?
没有
No. No.
- 所以她死了 - 是的
- So she's dead.  - Yes.
好的
Okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
再过一会儿 你将见证复活
A moment longer, and you will witness a resurrection.
她会回来 她会告诉我们
She'll return and she will tell us
她在来世看到了什么
what she saw in the afterlife.
先知动了吗
Has the Prophet moved?
没有
No.
你好
Hello?
- 没有 - 嗯嗯
- No. No. - Mmm-mmm.
好的 稍等片刻
All right. Just  un momentino.
再过一会儿
Only a moment longer.
长老们
The Elders?
- 我们尖叫 - 我们尖叫
- We scream. - We scream.
但要等他开门
But not until he answers the door.
- 他回来了 - 尖叫
- He's coming back. - Scream! Scream!
来了
Coming!
啊 抱歉
Ah! Sorry!
我在后面
I was at the back.
- 不 对不起 打扰你了 - 不
- No, I'm sorry to bother you. - No.
我只是在这个街区找
I'm just in the neighborhood looking for
我教会的两个年轻女士
two young ladies from my church.
哦
Oh.
一切都好吗
Is everything all right?
他们听不到我们说话
They can't hear us.
我相信一切都好
I'm sure everything's fine,
我只是想知道她们是否
I was just wondering if they...
顺便拜访
...stopped by.
不 很抱歉
No. I'm sorry to say,
你是今天第一个来我家拜访的人 所以
you are the first house caller I've had all day, so.
- 你看到这个了吗 - 它锁着
- Did you see this? - It's locked.
救命
Help.
我们可以拉地毯
We can pull the rug.
火柴
The matches.
我们点火
We start a fire,
用烟熏说话管 以确保
smoke out the speaking pipe to make sure
长老知道我们在这里
the Elder knows we're here.
好的 但是你确实要求
Okay. But you did ask
更多关于教会的信息 对吗
for more information on the church, correct?
这是哪个教会
Uh, this... this is the which church?
耶稣基督后期圣徒教会
The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.
是的
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
拉 小心
Pull. Careful.
我还能帮上什么忙吗
Is there some other way I can help?
你想用我的电话 报警吗
Do you want to use my phone, call the police?
- 我可以拿我的外套 - 不 没关系
- I could get my coat... - No, no. That's fine.
然后过来帮你四处看看
...and come help you look around.
不 我相信她们离这不远
No, no, no, no, no. I'm sure they're not far.
谢谢你抽出时间
Uh, thank you for your time.
好吧 祝你好运 是的 我是认真的
All right, well, good luck. Yeah, I mean that.
- 好的 - 嗯哼
- Okay. - Uh-huh.
不
No.
他来了
He's coming!
是吗 有进展吗
Yeah? Yeah? Any luck?
她动了
She moved.
- 你是什么意思 - 当我们离开的时候
- What do you mean? - When we were gone.
不 你记错了
No, you're remembering it wrong.
她根本没有动
She hasn't moved at all.
她的头不一样了
Her head is different.
- 她就在那里 - 不是
- That's where she was! - It's not!
姐妹 那不是我记得的样子 拜托
Sister, that's not how I remember it. Please!
拜托 来吧 救命
Please, just come on! Help!
把袖子举起来
Hold the sleeve up.
如果我不问你一个问题 那我就失职了
I'd be remiss if I didn't ask you one question.
你收到这本小册子了吗
Have you received this booklet?
我没有
I have not,
但我会看一看
but I will give it a look-see.
试试另一个
Try another.
我知道
I know.
集中注意力
Focus.
快点
Faster.
售票员
Conductor...
说 我的 名字
says... my... name.
白 云
White... clouds.
不是 天堂
Not... Heaven.
他们 拔掉
They... unplug...
我的大脑
my brain.
它
It is...
不是
not...
真的
real.
谢谢你 先知
And, thank you, Prophet.
我们非常感谢你穿越到
We are very grateful for your passage
另一边
to the other side.
你的预言将被记录到我们的礼拜文本中
Your prophecy will be recorded into our liturgical texts.
来 你一定累坏了 挽着我的胳膊
Come. You must be exhausted. Take my arm.
好了 现在
Well, now.
你看 这很有趣 因为
You see, this is rather interesting because...
我知道你们中的一个人一直在撒谎
I know that one of you has been lying
从你们第一次到这里开始
since you first got here.
你知道我是怎么知道的吗
And do you know how I know that?
对不起 我可以拿那个吗
Excuse me, can I... can I take that?
我知道 从方式上
I know from the way
火对你们每个人的反应
that the fire reacts to each of you.
A
A.
B
B.
是的 你们中的一个人有一个非常 非常
Yeah. One of you has a very, very...
非常大的秘密 但我们很快就会知道更多
...very big secret, but we will know more soon.
在你们看到一个女人死去之前会有
There will be before you saw a woman die
然后复活 之后也会有
and come back to life, and there will be after.
书会被写出来
Books will be written about it.
所以当我问的时候 要非常仔细地选择你的措辞
So choose your words very carefully when I ask,
你目睹了什么
what did you witness?
告诉我你看到了什么
Tell me. Tell me what you saw.
她怎么
How did she...
我不知道
I don't know...
如果你没有看到超验的东西
And if you didn't see something transcendental,
你一定要告诉我
you absolutely must tell me.
我不知道
I don't know.
因为如果我错了
'Cause if I'm wrong,
我需要听到它 这就是你在这里的原因
I need to hear it. That's why you're here.
这是一个精心设计的实验 我们是你的囚犯
It's a contrived experiment. We are your prisoners!
- 这没有意义 - 哦 呸
- It doesn't make sense... - Oh, pooh!
- 我们都是囚犯 - 让我们发表意见
- We're all prisoners together. - ...for us to have an opinion!
你现在一定知道 我们中的任何一个人都可以离开
You must know by now that any of us can leave
只要我们想 但是我们为什么要
whenever we want, but why would we want,
在我们所见之后
after what we've seen?
我看到了
I saw it. I saw it.
我听到她描述
I heard her describe
她在另一边的经历
what she experienced on the other side.
太好了 你听到了什么
Great! What did you hear?
她说有一个售票员
She said there was a conductor.
- 是的 - 她是指天使吗
- Yes. Yeah. - Did she mean angel?
她有一种分离感
She had a feeling of disassociation,
一种不真实的感觉
a feeling that something wasn't real.
就是这样
That's it.
所以现在你知道了
So now you know.
现在 我们知道了
Now, we know?
是的 现在 你知道了
Yeah, now, you know.
知道
Know?
我可以给你看上帝
I can show you God.
如果你愿意去死
If you're willing to die.
它可以是无痛的 它可以是暂时的
It... it can be painless. It can be temporary.
像先知一样 你可以被带回来
Like the Prophet, you can be brought back.
它不一定是可怕的
It doesn't have to be frightening at all.
我告诉你什么是可怕的
I'll tell you... I'll tell you what's frightening.
不知道才是可怕的
Not knowing is frightening!
我们从哪里来 我们在这里做什么
Where do we come from? What are we doing here?
我们的目的是什么
What's our purpose?
这些问题的恐惧是宗教存在的原因
The terror of those questions is why religions exist.
我可以为你回答这些问题
I can answer those questions for you.
我可以给你一种世界上任何宗教
I can give you a comfort no religion in the world
都无法给予你的安慰
is capable of giving you.
现在一切都说得通了
It all makes sense now.
我整晚都在问自己
I've been asking myself all night,
他怎么会让我们自杀成为我们的主意
how is he gonna make killing us our idea?
巴恩斯姐妹 你陷入了困境
Sister Barnes, you're in a muddle.
我知道 我不知道
I know. I can't tell
你在下国际象棋还是跳棋
if you're playing chess or checkers.
大富翁
Monopoly!
拜托 它就在那里
Come on, it was right there.
你没有给我们展示奇迹
You didn't show us a miracle.
好的 我给你展示了什么
Okay, what did I show you?
那不是奇迹
That wasn't a miracle.
你是这么说的 我给你展示了什么
So you say. What did I show you?
那不是奇迹
That was not a miracle!
我给你展示了什么
What did I show you?
这是一个魔术
It was a magic trick.
一个魔术
A magic trick?
你想知道为什么我们不谈论塔可钟吗
You wanna know why we don't talk about Taco Bell?
它在我四岁的时候杀死了我
It killed me when I was four years old.
五十人因大肠杆菌爆发住院
Fifty people were hospitalized from an E. coli outbreak.
学校的孩子们叫我塔可地狱
The kids at school called me Taco Hell
因为我在临床上已经死了
'cause I was clinically dead
当医生对我的肾脏进行手术时
while doctors operated on my kidneys.
当我死的时候
When I was dead,
我看到了你的先知所描述的一切
I saw exactly what your prophet described.
一道耀眼的白光
A blinding white light,
云 但不是天堂 一种想要回归的感觉
clouds, but not Heaven, a sense of wanting to return,
一种我的现实状态不真实的感觉
a feeling that my state of reality wasn't real.
那不是预言
That wasn't a prophecy.
那是一次濒死体验
That was a near-death experience.
当氧气离开你的大脑时
When the oxygen leaves your brain
或者你的心脏停止跳动 你的大脑
or your heart stops pumping, your mind
会创造出难以置信的东西
creates unbelievable things.
我认为你一直让这个女人处于死亡的边缘
I think you've been keeping this woman
为了问她一些问题
on the edge of death in order to ask her questions
关于毫无意义的幻觉
about meaningless hallucinations
这样你就可以证实你的想法
so that you can substantiate your idea
什么是唯一真正的宗教
of what the one, true religion really is.
你知道吗
Did you know...
当你记住某件事时
that when you remember something,
你实际上只记得
you're really only remembering
你最后一次记住那次经历
the last time you remembered that experience?
你实际上并没有回忆起那件事
You're not actually recalling the event.
所以你对在塔可钟死去的记忆
So your memory of dying at Taco Bell...
并不是真正的死亡
...isn't really of dying,
它是记忆的记忆
it's of the memory of the memory
的记忆的记忆的记忆
of the memory of the memory of the memory...
阻止我 的那件事
stop me... ...of that event.
所以你记住了一个错误的关联
So you're remembering a false correlation
与你刚刚目睹的经历
with the experience you've just witnessed.
但这是 这是正在发生的事情
But this, this is happening right now!
这就是为什么我认为 巴恩斯姐妹 帕克斯顿姐妹
That's why I think, Sister Barnes, Sister Paxton,
你们真的需要注意
that you really need to pay attention
因为我向你保证
because I promise you...
我们不是在谈论魔术
...we're not talking about a magic trick.
不
No,
我们在谈论魔法内衣
we're talking about magic underwear...
救救我 救命
Help me! Help!
她会回到我们身边的
She'll come back to us!
我保证
I promise!
帕克斯顿姐妹 不要害怕
Sister Paxton, do not be scared!
她会再次复活
She will rise again.
挑战他
Challenge him.
辩论
Debate.
挑战他
Challenge him.
来吧 巴恩斯姐妹
Come on, now, Sister B.
醒醒
Wakey-wakey!
哇
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
哇 不是那个
whoa, whoa, whoa! No, that's not it.
不是那个 那是一只脏兮兮的小狗
That's not it. That's a... a mucky pup.
让我们看看那个
Let's have that.
片刻 只需要片刻
Moments. It'll be moments.
让我们来一段你的鼓点 好吗
Let's have one of your drum rolls, yeah?
呜
Whoop!
嘿
Hey!
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
出问题了
Something is wrong.
我现在担心
I'm now worried...
她没有
that she's not...
回到我们身边
...coming back to us.
是的
Yeah.
哦 是的
Oh, yeah.
是的
Yep.
Yeah.
就是它
There it is.
不是
No, it isn't.
那是一条静脉
That was a vein.
啊哈
A-ha! A-ha.
植入物
The implant.
这就是她不能回到我们身边的原因
This is why she can't come back to us.
看一看
Take a look!
我很抱歉
I'm very sorry.
但是巴恩斯姐妹 她是一个程序
But Sister Barnes, she's a program.
她不是真的
She's not real.
你知道是什么暴露的吗
Do you know what gave it away?
蜡烛
The candles.
你在说什么 我不明白
What are you saying? I don't understand.
不 我知道
No, no, I know. I know. I know.
你怎么能
How could you?
你能给我解释一下吗
Can you explain it to me?
帕克斯顿姐妹 你
Are you, Sister Paxton,
熟悉道家的概念吗
familiar with the Daoist concept
“蝴蝶梦”
of "The Butterfly Dream"?
一只蝴蝶
A butterfly...
一只蝴蝶扇动翅膀 会引起台风吗
A butterfly flaps its wings and causes a typhoon?
那是“蝴蝶效应”
That is "The Butterfly Effect."
常见的错误 不 “蝴蝶梦”
Common mistake. No. "The Butterfly Dream"...
讲的是一位古代中国哲学家
...concerns an ancient Chinese philosopher
他问了自己以下问题
who asked himself the following question.
“我是梦见自己是一只蝴蝶的人吗
"Was I a man dreaming
还是我现在是”
"I'm a butterfly, or am I now..."
“一只梦见自己是人的蝴蝶”
"...a butterfly dreaming that I am a man?"
过来坐下
Come and sit down.
来吧 这里
Come on. Here.
这是我们
This is us.
你和我单独在一起
You and me alone together.
那是巴恩斯
That was Barnes.
再见 巴恩斯
Bye-bye, Barnes.
我得出了一个黑暗的结论
I have come to a dark realization
我们存在于一个如此先进的模拟中
that we exist inside a simulation so advanced
以至于我们无法区分现实生活和
that we cannot tell the difference between real life
人造梦境
and artificial dream.
你听到了先知 她说 “这不是真的”
You heard the Prophet. She said, "It is not real."
你看 火的动力学很难渲染
You see, fire dynamics are very difficult to render.
我注意到它在与模拟的 NPC
I've noticed this anomaly in its behavior
交互时的行为异常
when it interacts with simulated NPCs,
就像可怜的老巴恩斯姐妹
like poor old Sister B.
她不能回到我们身边 但是当你死的时候
She couldn't come back to us, but when you die,
手指 拜托 你将穿越死亡
finger, please, you will pass through death
然后醒来
and wake up...
进入现实世界
...into the real world.
你怎么看
What do you think?
是 不 也许
Yes, no, maybe?
嗯
Um...
那是一个理论
That's a theory.
好吧 是的 你非常欢迎
Well yeah, you're very welcome to...
挑战我的前提 我喜欢那样
to challenge my premise. I love that.
来吧
Go for it.
我不认为这是一个微芯片
I don't think this is a microchip.
哦
Oh?
我认为这是一种避孕措施
I think it's a contraceptive.
一个 节育植入物
A... a birth control implant.
嗯
Huh.
告诉我 你见过吗
Tell me, have you ever met
一个正在节育的摩门教传教士
a Mormon missionary who was on birth control?
“巴恩斯姐妹”有没有说过她在节育
Did "Sister Barnes" say she was on birth control?
我们的教会会让她
Our church would've made her
感到羞耻
feel ashamed about it,
她会感到太尴尬
and she would've been too embarrassed.
- 模拟理论是 - 啊
- Simulation theory is... - Ah!
“假设” 拜托 对不起 这不重要
"Hypothesis," please. Sorry, it doesn't matter.
模拟假设
Simulation hypothesis
是不可测试的 对吧
is not testable, is it?
不 这是一种信仰问题 就像任何宗教一样
No, it's a matter of belief, like any religion.
你要么相信它 绿色的门
You either believe it, green door,
要么你不相信它 紫色的门
or you don't believe it, purple door.
恕我直言
With all due respect,
我
I...
我不相信
I don't believe it.
我不够聪明 无法说出原因 我只是不相信
I'm not smart enough to say why, I just don't.
你相信我给你展示的奇迹吗
Do you believe the miracle that I showed you?
是的
Yes.
- 是吗 - 一开始
- Yeah? - At first.
但现在
But now?
我认为今晚发生了一些事情
I think something happened tonight
你没有预料到
that you didn't expect.
感觉你是在即兴发挥
It feels like you're improvising,
试图让我相信一个模拟理论
trying to convince me of a simulation theory
但这并不成立 我说得对吗
that's not sticking. Am I right?
你是在问我 你说得对
Uh, are you asking me if you're right
我是在即兴发挥
that I am improvising
还是你说得对 模拟叙事
or you're right that the simulation narrative
并不成立
is not sticking?
是的
Yes.
击掌
High-five.
所以 事实上 你同意你朋友的观点
So, in fact, you agree with your friend.
你认为先知只是在产生幻觉
You think that the Prophet was just hallucinating
一个毫无意义的濒死体验
a meaningless, near-death experience.
不
No.
我认为你调换了尸体
I think you switched the bodies.
我只是还没弄清楚怎么做到的
I just haven't figured out how yet.
我调换了
I switched...
尸体
the bodies?
长老到这里的时候 门铃响了
The doorbell rang when the Elder got here.
这把我们的注意力引到了楼梯上
Which drew our attention to the stairs.
你本来应该做好准备的
You would have been prepared for that.
当我们回到楼下时
When we came back downstairs,
我注意到那个女人和以前的位置不一样了
I noticed the woman wasn't in the same position as before.
很相似
It was similar...
她的头不一样了
Her head is different.
但并不完全一样
But it was not the exact same.
我认为另一个长得和她一模一样的女人
I think another woman who looked exactly like her
走进了地下室
came into the basement
通过一扇隐藏的门或其他什么
through a hidden door or something,
处理了她的尸体 然后在桌子旁取代了她的位置
disposed of her body and then took her place at the table.
我明白了
I see.
然后 一旦我们回到楼下
And then, once we got back downstairs,
她读了一段你为她
she read off a scripted prophecy
准备好的预言
that you prepared for her.
除了她最后说的一句话
Except the last thing she said was,
“这不是真的”
"It is not real."
不是 真实的
...not... real...
也许她想告诉我们
Maybe she was trying to tell us
那个奇迹不是真的
that the miracle wasn't real.
啊
Ah.
你明白我说的话的意思了吧
You see what I mean when I say
发生了你没有预料到的事情
something happened that you didn't expect?
我认为你给了她一个剧本 她脱稿了
I think you gave her a script, and she went off the book,
现在你正在努力挽回
and now you're trying to recover.
好吧 如果那是对的 那么
Well, if that's right, then, uh,
必须有另一条路可以进入这个地下室 对吧
there'd have to be another way into this basement, yeah?
我们要不要看看
Shall we have a look?
我不认为有
I don't think there is.
不
No.
我做得不太好
I'm not doing very well,
帕克斯顿姐妹
Sister Paxton.
除非
Unless...
这意味着
Which means that...
如果你是对的
there would have to be a dead body down there
那里应该有一具尸体
if you were right, huh?
对
Correct.
你将如何检验你的理论
How will you test your theory?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是你会进入那个洞里
But will you go into that hole and
看看那里有没有人吗
see if there's somebody down there?
如果我必须
If I have to.
你为什么要那样做
Why would you do that?
因为我想知道真相
Because I want to know the truth,
因为唯一的出路就是穿过
and because the only way out is through.
罗伯特·弗罗斯特
Robert Frost?
沼泽怪物
Swamp Thing.
不要进入那个地窖
Don't go into that cellar...
除非你准备好了
unless you are prepared
去发现唯一真正的宗教
to discover the one, true religion.
我就知道
I knew it.
嘿
Hey.
对不起 这么冷
Sorry about the cold.
你弄清楚了吗
Have you figured it out yet?
我想是的
I think so.
那是什么
So what is it?
什么是唯一真正的宗教 帕克斯顿姐妹
What is the one, true religion, Sister P?
是
It's...
当我们第一次到达时
When we first arrived,
你把我们单独留在你的客厅里
you left us alone in your living room.
我们以为你在和你妻子说话
We thought you were talking to your wife,
但你在做别的事情
but you were doing something else.
我是
I was.
你从巴恩斯姐妹的外套里拿了一把钥匙
You took a key from Sister Barnes' coat,
出去解锁我们的自行车并把它们藏起来
went outside to unlock our bikes and hide them.
我注意到你回来的时候头发是湿的
I noticed your hair was wet when you came back
带着饮料 就像你在暴风雨中一样
with the drinks, like you were out in the storm.
我猜你这样做 是因为你不想
You did this, I assume, because you didn't want
长老找到我们的自行车
the Elder to find our bikes
当他回来找我们的时候
when he came back looking for us.
但你还有别的事情要做
But there was something else on your mind.
是的
There was.
你把自行车钥匙
You returned the bike key
放回了错误的外套口袋
to the wrong coat pocket.
我们以为这是你犯的一个错误
We thought this was a mistake you made.
钥匙
Key.
但现在我知道不是了
But now I know it wasn't.
为什么
Why?
你把自行车锁给了你的一个先知
You gave the bike lock to one of your prophets,
指示他们用它锁上最后的地窖门
instructed them to lock the final cellar door with it.
但是为什么 为什么 我为什么要那样做
But why, why, why? Why did I do that?
因为你想让我知道
Because you wanted me to know
我现在站在这里的唯一原因
the only reason I'm standing here right now
是因为它正是
is because it is exactly
你想让我站的地方
where you want me to be standing.
我在这里不是因为我选择在这里
I'm not here because I chose to be.
我在这里是因为你让我选择在这里
I'm here because you made me choose to be.
哦
Oh.
因为你想让我相信 唯一真正的宗教是
Because you want me to believe the one, true religion is...
控制
...control.
完全正确
That is exactly right.
宗教只是一种控制系统
Religion is just a system of control...
没关系
It's okay.
我会帮助你
I'll help you.
不 你看 这就是有趣的地方
No, you see, that's what's so interesting.
他们不需要你的帮助
They don't want your help.
他们正是
They... they are exactly
他们选择的地方
where they chose to be.
但你杀了那个女人
But you killed that woman.
我不同意
I disagree.
她选择吃一个有毒的派
She... She chose to eat a poisoned pie
因为她有深刻的信仰
because of her profound faith.
这叫做喝 任何人
It is called drinking the... anyone?
库尔爱德饮料
Kool-Aid.
这是真的
It is true...
我让这些女士们感到有点冷
that I keep these ladies a little chilly,
还有点饿
and a little peckish,
为此我感到非常抱歉 对不起 女士们
for which I am very sorry. Sorry, ladies.
但这只是出于同样的原因
But only for the same reason
你们的教会去海地
that your church goes to Haiti
在飓风过后分发圣经
to give out Bibles after a hurricane.
控制更容易
It's easier to control
一个失去的人
someone who has lost...
一切
...everything.
你完全正确 她确实脱稿了
You're absolutely right. She did go off-book.
你为什么要这样做
Why do you do this?
问题是
The question is,
你们为什么都让我这样做
why do you all let me?
对不起
Sorry...
你在这里是因为别人的想法
You are here because the ideas of others
影响了你做出的每一个决定
have influenced every single decision you've made
自从你出生的那天起 我就能够预测
since the day you were born, and I've been able to predict
你今晚会做出的每一个决定 因为
every decision you would make tonight because of that.
你允许他们
You have allowed them
支配你生活的每一个决定
to dictate every decision of your life.
他们决定你崇拜谁
They decide who you worship,
你在哪里崇拜 你崇拜什么
where you worship, what you worship.
他们甚至支配你穿在衣服下面的衣服
They even dictate the garments you wear under your clothes.
什么
The what?
你的魔法内衣
Your magic underwear.
不
No... No...
No...
祈祷
Pray...
Pray.
为我们祈祷
Pray for us.
祈祷
Praying...
没有用
...doesn't work.
你听说过伟大的祈祷实验吗
Have you ever heard of the great prayer experiment?
他们把病人分成几组
They divided patients into groups.
接受祈祷的人和没有接受祈祷的人
Those who received prayers and those who didn't.
研究的结果是决定性的
The results of the study were conclusive.
它没有用
It doesn't work.
但我认为这很美
But I think it's beautiful
我们都为彼此祈祷
that we all pray for each other...
即使我们可能都知道
...even though we all probably know
这没有任何区别
it doesn't make a difference.
想想别人 而不是你自己 这很好
It's just nice to think about someone other than yourself.
即使是你自己
Even if it's you.
我很感激所有的考验
...I'm grateful for all the trials
你在我的生活中给了我
you've given me in my life.
感谢你为我铺设的道路
And for your path that you've laid out for me.
安静地
Quietly.
再见 姐妹
Goodbye, Sister.
♪ 妈妈 把这个徽章从我身上拿走 ♪
♪ Mama take this badge off me ♪
♪ 我不能再用它了 ♪
♪ I can't use it anymore ♪
♪ 天太黑了 看不见了 ♪
♪ It's getting dark too dark to see ♪
♪ 我觉得我在敲天堂的门 ♪
♪ I feel like I'm knockin' on Heaven's door ♪
♪ 敲天堂的门 ♪
♪ Knock-knock-knockin' on Heaven's door ♪
♪ 妈妈 把我的枪放在地上 ♪
♪ Mama put my guns in the ground ♪
♪ 我不能再开枪了 ♪
♪ I can't shoot them anymore ♪
♪ 那朵长长的乌云正在落下 ♪
♪ That long black cloud is comin' down ♪
♪ 感觉我在敲天堂的门 ♪
♪ Feels like I'm knockin' on Heaven's door ♪
♪ 敲天堂的门 ♪
♪ Knock-knock-knockin' on Heaven's door ♪